Hurry up! The flight leaves in four hours!
动作快，4小时后的班机
There could be traffic! The plane could leave early!
等叫到车可能都塞车了 飞机可能会提早起飞
In London,there could be a line at customs! Come on!
入境时可能会大排长龙，快点
Six-hour trip to London. That's a lot of Monica.
6小时的飞机，够她念了
What have you got there?
那是什么？
Condoms,dude.
保险套啊
Well,how come the writing is in spanish?
为什么印西班牙文？
Don't read my condoms.
别看我的套子
Passport,check. Camera,check. Traveler's checks,check.
护照打勾，相机打勾 旅行支票打勾
-Who are you saying "check" to? -Myself.
你在叫谁打勾？ 我自己
For remembering to pack a thing.
记得一样打一个勾
You do a good thing, you get a "check."
做一件好事就有个勾勾
Mom does it. I never realized it was weird.
这是妈的习惯，我没想过很怪
My mom used to put her head in the oven.
我妈都把头塞进烤箱里
Actually,only the one time. But it's pretty weird.
其实只有一次，不过蛮怪的
Are you ready yet?
准备好了吗？
-Got the tickets? -Right here. Check!
机票带了吗？ 在这里，打勾
It's all London,baby!
去伦敦罗，宝贝
Here we go.
走吧
Got your passport?
护照呢？
Third drawer of my dresser. You don't want to lose that!
梳妆台第三个抽屉 弄丢就糟了
There it is!
快去
The One With Ross' Wedding
本集播出：“罗斯的婚礼”
rainystar压制iPod-MP4
The vacuum's in my closet on the left side.
吸尘器在我的柜子里的左边
Garbage bags are next to the refrigerator.
垃圾袋在冰箱旁边
Rachel's gonna be here. Can't I just ask her?
瑞秋会在，我不能问她吗？
Yeah,okay. Give that a try!
好啊，你问啊
-Let's do it. -Cheerio!
走罗 好耶
London,baby!
伦敦，宝贝
That's not gonna get annoying.
我绝对不会觉得烦
London,baby!
伦敦，宝贝
You know what? I was wrong.
你知道吗？我错了
We're all here. Let's get going!
人都到了，我们走吧
I want to go over and hug you...
我很想过去抱你...
...and wish you luck, but I can't get up.
...恭喜你 但是我起不来
-I'll come hug you. -Great,can you bring me the paper?
那我过去抱你 太好了，帮我拿报纸
-Have a great wedding. -Thanks.
快快乐乐的结婚吧 谢谢
Chandler,I want to hug you too!
钱德，我也想抱你
You might as well bring my book from your apartment.
顺便去你家餐台把我的书拿来
-So we're off. -Have fun!
我们要走了 玩得开心点
-I can't believe you won't be there. -I know.
你居然不能去 是啊
Come. Why don't you come?
去嘛，你为什么不能去？
To London. Please? It would mean so much to me.
去嘛，一起去，我会很高兴
I gotta work. I'm sorry.
我要忙，对不起
Why can't you take a couple of days off?
为什么不能请两天假？
Because I can't. I told you.
我不行，我说过了
This is my wedding.
这是我的婚礼
Now we are late. Let's go,let's go!
真的来不及了，走走走
Fine,you'll watch it on video when we get back.
好吧，回来再让你看录影带
Here you go,Phoebe! Phoe-bo! Phoo-ba-la!
菲比，你的书书，苏苏 谢谢
You!
乖
Let's go!
走吧
Bye,Pheebs!
菲比再见 再见
London,baby!
伦敦，宝贝
Oh,God!
天哪
Do you need a hug?
你要抱抱吗？
You don't have to bring me anything.
你不必拿东西给我
Chandler,do something!
钱德，做点动作
-Do something! -I am. I'm ignoring you.
做动作啊 我有啊，我在不理你
I'll be the on-camera guy.
好吧，我来上镜头
All right. First stop...
好，第一站
...Westminster Abbey.
西敏寺
What is that?
那是什么？
That's London,baby!
伦敦啊，宝贝
All right,the hotel's here.
好，饭店在这里…
Wait.
等一下
We want to go
不对，我们要去…
I know.
我知道了
I'm gonna have to go into the map.
我得进入地图里
If you see a little version of me in there,kill it!
要是里面有个小钱德，杀了它
I got it.
我知道了
Here we go!
走吧
We're not gonna have to walk this way the entire time,are we?
我们不是要这样逛大街吧？
Man,you made me lose it!
你害我又乱了啦
That was all before 10:00.
…那时候才10点
The caterer rang. It'll be Chicken Kiev,not Tarragon.
外烩打来说龙蒿鸡换成基辅鸡
Then the florist said there are no tulips.
然后花匠说没有郁金香了
And the cellist has carpal tunnel syndrome
然后大提琴手得了 手腕隧道症候群…
Emily,honey. Okay?
艾蜜莉，亲爱的，好吗？
Well,up yours too!
我也去你的
-What? -Oh,that's not what it means.
什么？ 不是那个意思？
-No! That's "time out." -Sorry.
不，这是暂停的意思 对不起
Sweetie,relax. Everything will be great,okay?
放轻松，一切都会很美好
Come on,come on.
走吧
Chicken Kiev?
基辅鸡？
Doesn't that sound delicious at the last minute?
临时能有这道菜不错吧？
Salmon would be more elegant than chicken.
是啊，但鲑鱼会比鸡肉高雅
And you wouldn't worry about the salmonella.
也不必担心沙门氏菌 （沙门音同鲑鱼）
But of course...
不过...
...with salmon you would have to worry about the chicknella.
...鲑鱼也可能有鸡门氏菌
I can't wait to see where you're getting married.
真想赶快看到婚礼场地
It's beautiful. Her parents got married here.
也对，那里很美 她父母就在那里结婚
I can't believe they're tearing it down.
它居然要被拆了
It's really the most lovely building. It's over
你绝对没看过那么美的房子 就在…
Oh,my God!
天哪
It's nice.
还不错
Oh,my God!
我的天哪
What are we going to do?
怎么会这样？怎么办？
Everything's gonna be all right.
放心，不会有问题的
How's it gonna be all right?
怎么会没问题？
I see that.
说得也是
I talked to a guy, and I found out what happened.
我跟一个人问到了
They tore it down early.
怎么回事？ 提前进行拆除
All right!
漂亮
Westminster Abbey.
西敏寺
Hands down,best abbey I ever seen.
绝对是我见过最美的寺
What do you think of the Abbey?
你觉得西敏寺如何？
It's great! They're thinking of changing the name.
很宏伟，他们正打算改名
-To what? -To "Put the Camera Away"!
改成什么？ 改成“摄影机收起来”
Man,you are Westminster Crabby.
你真是西敏之狼
Don't worry,you'll find some place to get married.
放心，你们会找到场地的
Sorry. Lucky this dress is red.
抱歉，幸好红色沾血看不见
We can't find another place.
不可能找得到场地
Then we can't have the wedding.
婚结不成了
I've ordered chicken,and salad, and cake for a 150.
我订了一百五十人份的鸡肉 沙拉和蛋糕
What should be the most wonderfull day of my life...
一生中最快乐的日子
...is rapidly turning into just Sunday with a spectacular amount of food.
变成被食物淹死的星期天
You're gonna find a place.
你们会找到场地的
But even if,God forbid,you didn't, so you postpone the wedding.
就算找不到，那就延期嘛
Is that really so bad?
有那么糟糕吗？
Think about it. You could take all the time your needed to get everything that you want.
你想想，你可以筹备得很完整
You could have tulips. You could have salmon.
你可以订到郁金香…和鲑鱼
Salmon.
鲑鱼喔
I suppose it wouldn't be the end of the world.
延期确实死不了
Oh,thank you.
谢谢你
Look,either way you're gonna get married. You're gonna be happy.
总之你都会结婚，都会幸福
My mom's gonna like you better than me.
我妈都会比较喜欢你
Oh,God. She has told you that already,didn't she?
天哪，她已经这么说了对吧？
-Don't get up. What do you need? -Nothing.
别起来，你需要什么？ 没什么
Come on. I'm here to take care of you.
我就是留下来照顾你的 你需要什么？
Okay,I have a wedgie.
屁屁夹到内裤了
That is all you.
你自己解决
What do you want for lunch?
你中午想吃什么？
I don't know.
我不知道
I guess we have to eat.
我们是得吃饭
Yeah,I do.
我一定要吃
What's the matter?
怎么了？
I'm bummed the way I left things with Ross.
我应付罗斯的方式真差劲
I wish I didn't lie about work. He seemed so mad at me.
真后悔骗他说我要工作 他好像很气我
Don't be so hard on yourself. If I was still in love with some
别太苛责自己 要是我还爱的人要结婚…
Still in love with?
还爱？ 是啊
I'm not in love with Ross.
我才没有爱着罗斯
Good!
是没有
Yeah,me neither.
很好，我也没有
I'm not at the wedding, because he's my ex-boyfriend...
我不去是因为他是我的旧情人
...and that would be uncomfortable.
去了会很不自在
Not because I'm in love with him. I like Ross as much as anyone.
不是因为我还爱他 我跟大家一样喜欢罗斯
Clearly,I have feelings for him, but they don't mean love.
我对他的确有感情 但那不是爱
I mean,do I still have loving feelings for Ross? Yeah!
我对罗斯还有爱的感觉吗？有
I have continuing feelings of love.
我一直都有
But that doesn't mean I'm still in love with him.
但那并不表示我还爱着他
I have sexual feelings for him, but I do love him.
我对他还有“性”趣 但我当然爱他
Oh,my God!
天哪
Why didn't you tell me?
你为什么不告诉我？
-We thought you knew! -We?
我们以为你知道 我们？
We all know. We talk about it all the time.
对，我们都知道，还经常在聊
You all know? Does Ross know?
你们都知道？罗斯知道吗？
No! Ross doesn't know anything.
不，罗斯什么都不知道
And you didn't tell me!
你们居然没告诉我
We thought you knew. It's so obvious!
我们以为你知道，那么明显
It would be like telling Monica:
告诉你等于告诉摩妮卡
"Hey,you like things clean."
“喂，你很爱干净喔”
Or,you know,"Hey,Joey,you're gay."
或是“乔伊，你是同志喔”
What?
什么？
Oh,please,she's always got a broom in her hand.
拜托，她老是拿着扫把
What are you in the market for? Scarves,souvenir postcards....
想买什么？有围巾、明信片…
Check this out!
你看
That's the stuff! What do you think?
这个就对了，你觉得呢？
I won't need that "I'm with stupid" T-shirt anymore.
我不必买印着 “与笨蛋同行”的衣服了
Well,I like it. Here you go.
我喜欢，钱给你
You're not really buying that. Haven't you embarrassed me enough?
你不是来真的吧 你丢我的脸丢得还不够吗？
Oh,I embarrass you?
我丢你的脸？
How can I answer when I'm pretending I don't know you?
我假装不认识你，无法回答
He's just jealous. All Londoners wear them.
他是在嫉妒，伦敦人都在戴
Really? Then how come no one here anywhere is wearing one?
是吗？那这里怎么没人戴？
They're all tourists.
他们都是观光客
If you insist on wearing that in public...
如果你要当街戴着那顶帽子
...you're gonna spend the afternoon all by yourself.
下午你就自己去逛
If you make me choose between you and the hat,I choose the hat.
如果要在你和帽子之间做选择 我选择帽子
-Good choice. -Thanks.
够英明 谢了
That's it! I'm out of here. I won't be embarrassed any more.
够了，我要走了 我不想再丢脸了
How are you doing? Joey Tribbiani,America.
你好，乔伊崔比亚尼，美国人
I spoke to your dad, and you know what?
我跟你爸谈过，你猜怎样？
He thinks we can find a new hall.
他觉得可以另外找到场地
-We don't have to. -You found a place?
不必了 你找到地方了？
No,but Monica and I were talking...
没有，但摩妮卡和我讨论过
...and I was so upset about the hall being knocked down...
我为了礼堂被拆的事很烦
...and she suggested we put the wedding off for a bit.
结果她建议把婚期延后
She said what?
她说什么？
If I won't be happy with somewhere we'd find in a day...
如果我不喜欢临时找个地方
...we should postpone it.
我们就应该延期
Postpone it.
延期
Do you think Monica realizes how much our parents spent on this?
你觉得摩妮卡知道 我们爸妈花了多少钱吗？
Do you think my sister's teeny, tiny,little brain comprehends...
你觉得我妹的小脑袋能理解
...that people took time out of their lives...
大家特地挪出时间
...to fly thousands of miles to be here?
大老远飞来这里吗？
This isn't right.
这么做是不对的
I realize that people are gonna be disappointed.
我知道大家会失望
But I'm sure they'll come back.
但他们下次一定会再来
I can't ask people to do that. Would you?
我不能叫人家这么做，你会吗
Don't you point your pants at me!
别拿你的裤子指着我
We have no choice.
我们别无选择
Anywhere half-decent will have been booked.
像样一点的场地一定没空档
Don't you understand? This is our wedding!
你不懂吗？这是我们的婚礼
Postponing it is not an option. This is when we're getting married.
我只知道延期是不可能的 要结就现在结
-You're saying it's now or never? -I'm saying it's now.
意思是否则就不结罗？ 不，我是说现在就结
-Or? -There's no "or" in mine!
否则呢？ 我没说否则
What is wrong with these pants?
这条裤子是怎么搞的？
It's not the pants. It's you who's backwards.
不是裤子，是你本末倒置
If you don't understand how important this is to me...
要是你不懂这件事对我多重要
...perhaps we shouldn't marry at all!
或许我们根本不该结婚
Emily,no! Wait,stop! Emily,please
艾蜜莉，等一下，别走
Did shopping help you feel any better?
血拼完有舒服一点吗？
Manhattan doesn't have enough stores.
曼哈顿的店不够
I can help you get over him.
我可以帮你忘了他
You can?
真的？
I need you to bring me photos of Ross...
对，拿一张罗斯的照片
...and a small piece of chocolate...
一小片巧克力
...and a glass of tepid water.
和一杯温水来
Is this where you throw stuff...
是不是要...
...in a bag with graveyard dirt and hang it from a north-facing tree?
...跟墓地的土装在一起 挂在面北的树上？
Only if you have the hiccups too.
要是你也在打嗝的话
The chocolate and water are for me. I didn't feel like getting up.
照片是给你的，其他是我要的 我只是不想起来
I'll show you a picture of Ross.
我给你看一张罗斯的照片
And you remember all the bad things about him.
你要去想他不好的地方
-Focus on his flaws. -I can do that.
专心想他的缺点 没问题
I did that while we were going out.
我们交往时我就这样
Before we start,I want to say, for the record,I love Ross.
好，首先我想先声明 我爱罗斯
He's such a great guy.
他真的好棒
Close your eyes.
好，闭上眼睛
Imagine that you're with Ross.
想像你跟罗斯在一起
Imagine that you're kissing him.
想像你在亲他
You're running your hands all over his body.
你的手在他的身上游移
You run your hands through his hair but
你的手抚弄他的头发
Gross! It's some kind of grease.
但是好恶！是某种油
I don't know.
我不晓得
His hair never bothered me that much.
他的头发没那么困扰我
It was more crunchy than it was greasy.
那应该算是硬而不是油
This will be harder than I thought.
好吧，难度比我想的还高
Let's try some aversion therapy.
试试厌恶疗法好了
Look at the picture.
看着照片 好
How do you feel now?
现在觉得怎样？
Well,I like you less.
我比较不喜欢你了
在英国玩也一样难玩
Sorry.
抱歉
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have said you were embarrassing me.
我才抱歉 我不该说你丢我的脸
That wasn't cool.
那样很过份
If it makes you feel any better, I've had a really lousy day.
如果你会高兴一点 我今天过得很悲惨
Me too.
我也是
-Yeah? -No!
真的？ 才怪
I had the best day ever!
我玩得超过瘾的
Dude,check this out!
你看
有你的这段就快转，无聊死了
Tell my friend you like my hat.
告诉我朋友你喜欢我的帽子
-What's your friend's name? -Chandler.
好，你朋友叫什么？ 钱德
Hi,Chandler.
钱德你好
-That's -That's Fergie,baby!
那不是… 那是佛姬，宝贝
Joey says you don't like his hat, but I think it's kind of dashing.
乔伊说你不喜欢他的帽子 但我觉得蛮时髦的
So I hear you're single now.
听说你恢复单身了
- Yeah,I don't like the hat that much. -Okay.
我对帽子没喜欢到那个程度
When did you? How?
你什么时候… 怎么会…
I was trying to get to Buckingham Palace.
我想去白金汉宫
So I'm in my map and
就进入地图，然后…
I understand you had a talk with Emily.
听说你和艾蜜莉谈过
Yes,I did.
没错
And you are welcome.
不客气
Am l?
是吗？
Was it your idea to postpone the wedding?
是你提议把婚期延后的？
-I'm going to the bathroom. -Wait up!
我要上厕所 等我
Since you're the fix-it lady, here's a pickle:
既然你这么会解决问题 问题来了
What do you do when the bride says she doesn't want the wedding at all?
当新娘说她不想结婚时 你怎么办？
She said that? Why?
她这么说？ 对 为什么？
I don't know. I said it was stupid to put off the wedding...
我不知道 我说为了礼堂被拆就延期很蠢
...and she,like,flipped out.
她就捉狂了
Oh,my God! You're even dumber than I am.
天哪，你比我还笨
Excuse me?
什么？
How long have you been planning this wedding?
你筹备这次婚礼多久了？
I don't know. A month?
不晓得，1个月吧
Emily's probably been planning it since she was 5.
艾蜜莉可能从5岁就在计划了
Ever since the first time she hung a pillowcase from her head.
从她第一次把枕头套 披在头上开始
That's what we did.
女生都这样
We dreamed about the perfect wedding.
我们梦想办一场完美的婚礼
In the perfect place.
在一个完美的场地
With the perfect four-tiered wedding cake.
有一个完美的四层结婚蛋糕
With the little people on top.
上面有小人偶
But the most important part...
但最重要的...
...is that we had the perfect guy...
...是有个完美的男人
...who understood just how important all that stuff was.
了解这一切对我们有多重要
I had no idea.
我都不知道
That pillowcase thing,I thought you were doing The Flying Nun.
我以为你披枕头套 是在学“快乐的修女”
Sometimes we were.
有时候是啦
Come on.
别哭了
Help me figure out what to do.
帮我想想办法
Pretty intense,huh?
场面蛮紧张的 是啊
I hope Ross didn't think we left because we were uncomfortable here.
希望罗斯不会以为 我们是怕尴尬才进厕所
I hope he did.
希望他就是这么想的
I thought of a good flaw. Ross pops his gum.
我想到一个缺点了 罗斯吃口香糖会吹泡泡
Oh,right.
没错
-Wait a minute. I do that too. -I know,it drives me crazy.
等等，我也会 是啊，我超受不了的
I'll get it.
我来接
Pheebs,it's Joey.
菲比，我是乔伊
Hey,Joey!
乔伊
I saw someone that looks just like you on the subway.
我在地铁看到一个很像你的人
I was going to say hi,then I figured he doesn't care he looks like you.
我正想打招呼 又想到他不会在乎他长得像你
That just cost me 4 bucks.
你讲了我4块钱了
I called to see how the chick and the duck are doing.
我打来问小鸡小鸭好不好
They're having fun with Aunt Phoebe. Aunt Rachel hasn't been helpful.
它们跟菲比阿姨玩得很开心 瑞秋阿姨没什么用
So do you miss me?
你想我吗？
Kind of,but I've been having too much fun.
有点，但我玩得太高兴了
You're not homesick yet?
你还没想家？
I don't think so.
没有，应该没有
Well,the seven of us miss you.
我们七个都很想你
-Who's seven? -Me,Rachel...
哪七个？ 我，瑞秋，
...the birds,the babies.
鸡鸭，宝宝
The babies miss me?
宝宝也想我？
Of course they do,or I'm just really hungry.
当然想，不然就是我太饿了
Pizza guy's here!
披萨来了
You ordered pizza without me?
你们趁我不在叫披萨？
But we were thinking about you. We ordered the Joey Special.
对，但我们有想着你 我们点了欢乐（乔伊）套餐
Two pizzas?
两个披萨？
-Gotta go! Talk to you later. -Wait!
对，我得挂了，再聊 等等
Where did you get it from?
你们叫哪一家的？
（欢乐酒店）
And they're always glad you came
他们永远欢迎您的光临
You want to be where you can see
要去就去一个
Your troubles are all the same
让你看得开的地方
You want to be Where everybody knows your name
要去就去一个 大家都认识你的地方
Why have you brought me here?
你带我来这里干什么？
You'll see.
等着瞧
This wedding won't happen.
我们不会结婚了
Ross.
罗斯
But imagine a lot more lights...
好，但想像更多灯火
...and fewer bricks...
少一点砖瓦，
...and flowers and candles.
还有鲜花蜡烛
And the musicians can go over here.
乐队可以摆在这里
The chairs can face this way and
椅子可以朝这边，然后…
You go.
你讲
But if you don't love this, we'll do it any other place or time.
不过要是你不喜欢 我们就改时间改地点
Really,it's fine.
真的没关系
Whatever you want.
你高兴就好
It's perfect.
这样很完美
And,I don't know,if it rains
我不知道，要是下雨…
Then we'll get wet.
那就淋湿吧
I don't even have a date.
我连男朋友都没有
Do you remember where the duck food is?
菲比 怎样？你记得饲料在哪里吗？
In the guys' apartment, under the sink. Why?
记得，在男生那边的水槽下面 怎么了？
Because I'm going to London.
因为我要去伦敦
What? What do you mean?
什么？什么叫你要去伦敦？
I have to tell Ross I love him.
我得告诉罗斯我爱他
Take care and don't have the babies till I get back.
保重，等我回来再生
But what about all the finding-his-flaws stuff we've been doing?
那我们想了半天他的缺点呢？
Yeah,that didn't work.
没用
You can't go. Ross loves Emily.
你不能去，罗斯爱的是艾蜜莉
I know,but I have to tell him how I feel.
我知道 但我得告诉他我的感觉
He deserves all the information to make an informed decision.
他应该知道所有状况 好做出知道状况的决定
You're going because you hope he'll say:
才怪，你去是希望他说
"l love you too. Forget the British chippy."
“我也爱你” “别理那个英国妹了”
You think he will?
你觉得他会吗？
No,because he's in love with the British chippy!
不会，因为他爱那个英国妹
You're just gonna mess with his head and ruin his wedding.
你去了只会把他搞乱 毁了他的婚礼
It's too late! You missed your chance.
太迟了，你错过机会了
I'm sorry. This must be hard.
抱歉，你一定很难受
But it's over.
但已经结束了
No,it's not over until someone says,"l do."
不，有人说“我愿意” 才算结束
I do! I do!
我愿意！我愿意…
Like I can really chase you. I'm carrying a litter!
谁追得上你，我怀了一窝猪仔
The Waltham residence.
华森公馆
Is this Emily's parents' house?
是艾蜜莉的父母家吗？
This is the housekeeper speaking.
我是管家
And,by the way,that is not how one addresses a person on the telephone.
还有，小姐 讲电话不能这样讲
First one identifies oneself...
先表明身份
...and then asks for the person with whom one wishes to speak.
再请你想找的人过来
What are you saying?
你在说什么？
Now,let us try that again,shall we?
我们重来一次
No!
不！
Oh,my God!
天哪
-The Waltham residence. -Hello.
华森公馆
This is Phoebe Buffay. I was wondering,please...
我是菲比布非，我是想麻烦你
...if it's not too much trouble,please...
如果不是很麻烦的话
...might I speak with Miss Emily Waltham,please?
我能和艾蜜莉华森小姐通话吗
Miss Waltham is at the rehearsal dinner.
华森小姐去排练餐会了
And it is not polite to make fun of people. Goodbye.
嘲弄别人的口音是不礼貌的 再见
I'll be nice,I swear. Could you just give me the number for where they are?
不！我会有礼貌，我发誓 可以把现场的电话给我吗？
I'm afraid I'm not at liberty to divulge that information.
我恐怕没有权利泄露这项讯息
Somebody is on their way to ruin the wedding,and I have to warn somebody.
有人正要去破坏婚礼 我得警告他们
So if you don't give me that number, I'm gonna come over there...
你不给我号码，我就杀到伦敦
...and I'm gonna kick your snooty ass all the way to New Gloukenshire!
把你一脚踹到新咕噜肯夏去
Hello? Hello?
She knew I could kick her ass.
她知道我说到做到
-Hi,sweetheart. -Mom,Dad.
乖儿子 妈 爸
Sorry we're late.
抱歉迟到了
My fault. I insisted on riding the tube.
是我不好，我坚持要坐管子
Judy,the kids!
茱蒂，孩子都在
Jack,that's what they call the subway.
杰克，那是地铁的俗称
-I thought -Dad,we got it.
我以为… 爸，我们懂
Here comes my dad and stepmom.
我爸和继母来了
Mr. and Mrs. Geller.
伯父伯母，
-This is Steven... -Hello,darling.
这是史帝芬…
...and Andrea Waltham.
和安瑞亚华森
Very nice to meet you.
幸会
Darling,the Gellers.
老婆，是盖勒家的人
Darling,it's the Gellers.
老婆，是亲家
She's very self-involved. I should never have married her.
她只想着自己，我不该娶她的
-It's the Gellers. -Where?
你说什么？是盖勒家的人 在哪里？
That's one and that's another one.
那边一个，那边一个
Lovely to meet you.
很高兴认识你们
Nice of you to offer to pay for half the wedding.
谢谢你们出一半的钱
The hell with tradition. We're happy to do it.
不客气，去他的习俗 我们很乐意
We know how expensive weddings can be.
我们知道结个婚有多花钱
Besides,this may be the only wedding we get to throw.
而且以后可能就没机会了
A joke that's funny in all countries.
真是个世界通行的笑话
Sir?
您要吗？
-What's in it? -Goat cheese,watercress and pancetta.
里面包什么？ 羊酪、水田芥和培根
That's not food.
这能吃吗？
Everything's different here. I want to go home.
这里的东西都不一样 我想回家
I miss my family,the coffeehouse.
我想念我的家人，想念咖啡馆
I can't even remember what Phoebe looks like!
我连菲比的长相都不记得了
It's been three days.
我们才来3天
Okay,you're just homesick.
你只是想家了
Would you just try to relax and just enjoy yourself?
放轻松，好好玩就对了
You're different here too.
连你都变了
You're mean in England!
你在英国好坏
What the hell?
搞什么？
What's up,Dad?
怎么了？
This bill for my half of the wedding. It's insane.
我的这份帐单 太扯了
How can it be so much? The reception's at their house.
怎么会这么贵？ 请客是在家里请
Flowers,liquor. Re-carpet first floor?
花，酒，一楼重铺地毯？
New guest bath,landscaping.
新的客用浴室，造景
I'm paying to remodel this guy's house.
我在出钱让他们装修
I'm gonna give that son of a bitch a piece of my mind.
我要把那个混蛋骂一顿
Please.
爸，别激动
I don't want anything to upset Emily tonight.
我不想让艾蜜莉不开心
She's had a hard enough couple of days as it is.
她这两天已经够心烦了
Here. Let me go talk to him.
给我，我去跟他谈
You tell him no one takes advantage of the Gellers.
告诉他谁也别想占盖勒家便宜
Sometimes I forget how powerful you can be.
杰克 有时候我都忘了你多有气概
And I'm gonna go get drunk.
我要去喝个烂醉
-Hello. -Hello.
你好 你好
When is your next flight to London?
下一班飞伦敦的班机？
There's one leaving in 30 minutes.
半小时后有一班
And I do have one seat left.
还剩一个空位
Thank you,thank you.
谢谢你
The last-minute fare on this ticket is $2700.
临时票的价钱是2700元
Huh. How about 600?
卖我6百如何？
-Sorry. -How about 600 and these earrings?
抱歉 6百再加这对耳环
They prefer it if I don't barter.
公司是觉得最好不要
I don't think I have enough left on my credit card.
我的信用卡额度不够
You can split it with another card.
你可以分两张刷
How about five?
五张可以吗？
Thank you.
谢谢
I'm just going to need to see your passport.
请出示护照
I don't have it,but I can tell you exactly where it is on my nightstand.
我没带，不过我可以告诉你 它就在我的床头柜上
You know what? I have my driver's license.
这样吧，我有驾照
And I have a 20.
还有一张20元钞票
Face it. My father is not going to pay for the built-in barbecue.
我爸不会付内建烤炉的钱
And believe me,you can kiss your gazebo goodbye.
还有，凉亭也免谈
I might be able to get you the new lawn.
我或许可以争取到新草皮
Then you have to give us the lawn ornaments.
那也得给草坪的装饰品
I go back there with lawn ornaments, he'll laugh in my face.
我要是答应会被我爸笑死
This is ridiculous. I mean,we had an agreement.
太扯了，大家都说好了
Will you say something,Steven?
史帝芬，你说句话好吗？
Don't take that tone with me.
别对我这么不客气
All right,you can.
好吧，随你
Thank God!
菲比 谢天谢地
You changed your mind.
你改变心意了
You probably want to be alone, you don't want to talk about it.
你现在或许想静一静
You're doing the right thing.
没关系，你这么做是对的
Where are you going?
再见 等等，你要去哪里？
What are you doing? No,wait.
你又想干什么？等等
Why am I always pregnant when she does that?
为什么每次她这样 我都在怀孕
I'd like to make a toast to Ross and Emily.
我想敬罗斯和艾蜜莉一杯
My big toast is tomorrow.
我明天会正式敬酒
This is kind of my little toast, or Melba toast,if you will.
今天是非正式敬酒 也就是随便敬敬
Okay.
好，
I've known Ross for a long time. I knew him when he was with his first girlfriend.
我跟罗斯认识很久了 他第一次交女朋友我都知道
I thought things were going to work out for him,until the day he over-inflated her.
我以为他们很顺利 直到那天他替她“充气”
Oh,dear God!
天哪
Hello,Waltham lnteriors.
华森府邸
Mrs. Waltham.
华森太太
I need to speak with one of the best men or Ross' sister,Monica.
我想找罗斯的伴O之一或妹妹摩尼卡
-Who is this? -Phoebe,one of Ross' best friends.
你是谁？我是菲比布非 罗斯最要好的朋友之一
How did you get this number?
你怎么知道这个号码？
I got it from your maid. She's a bitch,but I wore her down.
跟你的女佣问的 她很贱，但我比她更贱
If you're one of Ross' best friends, why aren't you here?
既然是罗斯的朋友怎么没来？
I can't fly. I'm having my brother's babies.
我不能坐飞机 我怀了我弟的孩子
Am I on the radio?
是广播节目吗？
Can I talk to one of them? It's important.
不是 我可以找他们吗？我有要紧事
I'm bored of you now. I'm going to cut you off.
我对你没兴趣了，我要挂了
Oh,okay,I'm going to have to kick her ass too.
我也要踹她
We're excited that Ross and Emily are getting married at Montgomery Hall.
很高兴罗斯和艾蜜莉 要在蒙哥马利礼堂结婚
To think,my friend getting married in Monty Hall.
我朋友要在“蒙帝霍尔”结婚 （霍尔字同礼堂）
Come on,Monty Hall!
拜托，蒙帝霍尔啊
Let's Make a Deal. Come on,you people!
“大家来挑战”主持人啊 笑一下吧
All right,forget it. Congratulations,Ross and Emily.
算了，恭喜 罗斯和艾蜜莉
Best man number two,Joey Tribbiani.
伴O二号，乔伊崔比亚尼
I'm not good with the jokes like Chandler here.
我没钱德那么会说笑话
Congratulations to the happy couple.
我只想说恭喜这对幸福的新人
I first met Ross in this coffeehouse back home.
我在我家附近咖啡馆认识罗斯
Home.
家
New York City.
纽约市…
Where everybody knows my name.
在那里大家都认识我
Anyway...
总之...
...I love you guys.
我爱你们
But not as much as I love America.
但是我更爱美国
Can we please go home now?
我们回家了好不好？
Are you going home?
你要回去了？
I was hoping to get to know you better.
我正想进一步了解你
I'm not going anywhere,sweetheart.
美人，我哪儿也不去
I was laughing.
我有笑啊
Out loud?
有笑出声吗？
I didn't want everyone to think I was stupid.
我不想让别人觉得我很白痴
So how are you?
你好吗？
My mother's driving me crazy. But Ross is getting married. I'm happy.
我妈快把我逼疯了 但是我很替罗斯高兴
I'm not going to let anything spoil that.
我不会让任何人扫我的兴
I just want to say that Ross is a wonderful young man.
我只想说罗斯真是个好青年
Thanks. We like him.
谢谢，我们都喜欢他
My God! You must have been a teenager when you had him.
天哪，你生他时一定才十几岁
There's no way in hell I'm paying for it.
我绝对不会付钱
Look,we're down to just one point.
好，我只问一件事
Could we please just settle it after the wedding?
能不能婚礼后再解决？
Fine,but I'm not paying for your wine cellar...
好，但我绝不付酒窖的钱
...you thieving, would-be-speaking- German-if-it-weren't-for-us, cheap little man!
靠美国才没被德国殖民的小人
The guy was hammered. There's no way you look like Ross' mother.
那砘镒砘枇 你怎么可能像罗斯的妈
-Then why would he say it? -Because he's crazy!
那他为何会认错？ 因为他疯了
He came up to me earlier and thanked me for my very moving performance in Titanic.
之前他还谢谢我 在“铁达尼号”里演得很棒
My mother's right. I'll never get married.
我妈说得对，我嫁不出去了
You know what,that is
这么说就…
Who wouldn't want you?
谁不想要你？
Please! I'm a single mom with a 30-year-old son.
拜托 我是个儿子30岁的单亲妈妈
-Hi,I'm back. Listen,I need to -Hello.
我回来了，听着，我得… 你好
Hello. I need to get on that 11:00 flight.
你好，我得赶11点那班飞机
I'm afraid that plane's already pulled away from the gate.
那架班机已经起飞了
You're going to have to call that plane and tell them to swing around and pick me up.
你得叫他们掉头回来接我
-Can't do that. -Sure,you know what?
我不能那么做
We'll just tell them that there was, like, a problem with, like, the engine.
当然可以，就说引擎有问题
I'm afraid I'm going to have to ask you to step aside, miss.
我恐怕得请你让开
Look,if I don't get to London he is gonna marry that other girl.
我不赶去伦敦，他会娶别人
Can't imagine why.
真不懂是为什么
All right. You know what?
你知道吗？
I am not leaving here until you call that plane back.
你不把架飞机叫回来我就不走
（暂停服务）
I'm getting married today!
我今天要结婚了
Morning.
早啊，罗斯
-I'm getting married today! -Yeah,you are.
我今天要结婚了
Do you think he knew I was here?
你觉得他有发现吗？
-Excuse me. -Yeah.
抱歉 是
If you're going to do that throughout the flight,tell me now...
要是你打算一路敲打到伦敦 现在就说
...so that I can take a sedative.
我好吃镇静剂
Or perhaps slip you one.
或是给你一颗
I'm sorry. I'm very sorry. Sorry.
对不起，非常抱歉
It's just,I'm kind of excited.
我只是有点兴奋
I'm going to London...
我要去伦敦...
...to tell this guy that I love him.
...告诉一个人我爱他
Well,I've never done that with you before.
我没跟你做过这档事
是没有
So how are you?
你怎样？
You okay?
还好吗？
Yeah. Yeah. You?
很好，你呢？
Oh,yes. Yes.
很好…
You?
你呢？
We did you.
我们问过你了
Well....
-I better get going. -Absolutely.
我该走了 好，当然
Could you not look?
你能不能不要看？
I don't want to look.
我不想看
Where the hell have you been?
你死哪去了？
I spent the night out. I met this cute bridesmaid. She is so...
我没回来睡 我认识了可爱的伴娘，她好…
I don't want to hear it!
我不想听
Pheebs,you know you're still my number-one girl.
菲比，我最喜欢的还是你
No. No. We have an emergency. Rachel's coming to London.
不，出事了，瑞秋跑去伦敦了
Great!
太好了
No,it's not great. She's coming to tell Ross that she loves him.
一点也不好 她要去告诉罗斯她爱他
But he loves Emily.
但是罗斯爱艾蜜莉
I know that!
我知道
You have to stop her. She's going to ruin the wedding.
你得阻止她，她会破坏婚礼
Okay.
好
-All right,so -Hold on,hold on.
所以… 等等
Rachel coming.
瑞秋来了
Do...
想…
...something.
...办法
I've done my part,okay?
我该做的都做了
It's your responsibility now. The burden is off me.
现在该你负责 我卸下这个责任了
-Right? -Right.
对吧？ 对
So tell me about this girl.
说说这个伴娘吧
And so then I realized, all the stuff that I had been doing...
结果我发现我的一切举动
...proposing to Joshua,lying to Ross about why I couldn't come to the wedding...
向约书亚求婚、骗说我要忙
-...was all just a way -Oh,oh,oh,oh!
都只是一种…
I'm sorry,can I interrupt?
抱歉，可以打个岔吗？
I just want to say that you are a horrible, horrible person.
你真是个很糟糕，很糟糕的人
Pardon me?
你说什么？
You say you love this man,and yet you're about to ruin the happiest day of his life.
你说你爱这个人 却要去破坏他的大喜之日
I'm afraid I have to agree with your friend Pheebs.
我不得不同意你朋友菲比的话
This is a terrible, terrible plan.
这是个很差劲，很差劲的打算
-But he has to know how I feel. -But why?
但他必须知道我的感受 为什么？
He loves this Emily person. No good can come of this.
他爱这个艾蜜莉 这么做绝对没好处
-Well,I think you're wrong. -Oh,no.
我觉得你错了 才怪
Well,he doesn't really love her. It's just a rebound thing from me.
他并非真的爱她 只是失去我需要寄托
-You'll see. -Fortunately I won't.
你等着瞧 幸好我看不到
And by the way,it seems to be perfectly clear that you were on a break.
还有，你们当时显然是分手了
Do something.
想办法
Something.
办法
-Have you seen Monica? -I'm not seeing Monica!
你有看见摩妮卡吗？ 我没有在跟摩妮卡交往
-What? -What?
什么？ 啥？
We gotta find her. Rachel's coming to tell Ross she loves him.
我们得找到她 菲比说瑞秋要来向罗斯表白
-Oh,my God! -I know. Do you know where Monica is?
天哪 没错，所以要找到摩妮卡 你知道她在哪里吗？
No. What's with the third degree? Why not just shine a light in my eyes?
不知道！你在逼问什么？ 干脆拿灯照我的眼睛算了
Oh,my God!
我的天哪
It's like a fairyland.
跟仙境一样
I know. It's horrible,isn't it?
是啊，很恐怖吧？
I love it. I only hope my wedding looks this good.
我好喜欢 希望我的婚礼也能这么美
-I just hope -You can let some of them go by.
我觉得… 有些话就别接了
Start looking out for Rachel.
开始注意瑞秋
I'll cover the front door. You watch that big hole.
我守前门 你守后面那个大洞
And I got Chandler covering Ross.
罗斯那里有钱德顾着
Why would I care where Chandler is?
我干嘛管钱德在哪里？
You know...
...sometimes I don't even like Chandler.
有的时候我根本不喜欢钱德
Okay.
好
I do.
我愿意…
我愿意
-You're right. It's the second one. -Right?
没错，第二个比较好 是吗？
Hello,Joey.
乔伊
Hey,Felicity.
费丽西蒂
I thought about you all day.
我整天都在想你 是吗？
Talk New York to me again.
再跟我讲讲纽约的事
Forget about it.
别管纽约了
How you doing?
你好吗？
There's nothing to discuss. We're not paying for your wine cellar.
没什么好谈的 我们不会付酒窖的钱
You have to meet me in the middle here.
你们总得折衷一下
My foot's gonna meet the middle of your ass.
你再罗唆我就踹你的屁眼
-What's going on? -Everything's under control.
怎么了？ 没事，一切都在掌握中
You want a piece of me,sir? Is that what you're saying?
你想干架？你是这个意思吗？
That's it! Parents! Parents! Back away!
够了，双方家长，退后
This is our wedding day!
这是我们的大喜之日
From now on,everyone gets along.
你们给我好好相处
And if I hear one more word...
谁再多说一个字
...no grandchildren! That's right!
就别想抱孙子，没错
-Okay,okay. -Sorry,old boy.
知道了 抱歉
I could kill you with my thumb, you know.
我用大拇指就能扳倒你
What was all that about?
这是怎么回事？
It was this disagreement over
只是一些费用上的…
My God! You look beautiful.
天哪，你真美
You're not meant to see me before the wedding. It's bad luck.
行礼前看到新娘会不吉利
I think we've had all the bad luck we're going to have.
我们的恶运应该都用完了
My God,Rachel!
天哪，瑞秋
You're here. I can't believe it.
你来了，我真不敢相信
What happened? Why are you here?
你怎么跑来了？
I just came to
我只是来…
I just needed to tell you...
我只是得告诉你…
...congratulations.
恭喜你
Hello,Waltham lnteriors.
华森府邸
Mrs. Waltham? It's Phoebe.
华森太太吗？又是我，菲比
Why?
怎么又是你？
Can I talk to one of the best men? This is going to be the last time.
我可以跟伴O之一说话吗？ 我保证这是最后一次
There's a girl on the phone for you.
有个女生找你
Great!
真好
It's Phoebe.
乔伊，是菲比
Did you stop Rachel?
你有堵到瑞秋吗？
No,but it's okay. She just came in and gave him a hug. That's it.
没有，但没事 她只有抱抱他而已
-Nothing got ruined? -No.
没有破坏什么？ 没有
That's so great!
太好了
So,what's going on now?
现在怎么样了？
I'm walking down the aisle.
我正在走红毯
Still walking.
还在走
I'm about to pass the bridesmaid I hooked up with last night.
我正要经过昨晚那个伴娘面前
Hey.
I just told her "hey."
我刚跟她说嗨
I'm at the front with Ross.
我跟罗斯站在一起了
It's Phoebe!
是菲比
He looks pretty mad.
他看起来很不爽
I better go.
我得挂了
Wait! Hold it up so I can listen.
等一下！拿着让我听
-What we did last night was -Stupid.
昨晚的事真是… 愚蠢
Totally crazy, stupid.
既夸张又愚蠢
What were we thinking?
我们在想什么？
I'm coming over tonight though, right?
我晚上去找你，好吗？
Definitely.
当然好
Friends,family...
各位亲朋好友
...we are gathered to celebrate...
我们今天齐聚一堂
...the joyous union of Ross and Emily.
庆祝罗斯与艾蜜莉缔结良缘
May the happiness of today...
愿今朝的幸福...
...be with them always.
...永远与他们同在
Now,Emily,repeat after me.
艾蜜莉，跟我复述
-l,Emily... -l,Emily...
我，艾蜜莉…
-...take thee,Ross... -...take thee,Ross....
嫁给你，罗斯…
...as my lawfully wedded husband, in sickness and in health...
做我合法的丈夫 无论贫病...
...till death parts us.
至死不渝
As my lawfully wedded husband, in sickness and in health...
做我合法的丈夫 无论贫病...
...until death parts us.
至死不渝
Now,Ross.
罗斯
Repeat after me.
跟我复述
I,Ross...
我，罗斯…
...take thee,Emily...
迎娶你，艾蜜莉…
...take thee,Rachel
迎娶你，瑞秋…
Emily.
艾蜜莉
Shall I go on?
还要继续吗？
"Mother,Mother,Pizza,Pizza," take one.
第一次…
Oh,the band's ready? We gotta do what the band says,right?
乐队准备好了？ 乐队怎么说我就怎么做
I don't care about the stupid band!
我才懒得管乐队呢
-Well,it's getting late. -Here we go.
咱们去上床
Actually,you guys mind staying here with me for a while?
你们可以陪我一下吗？
You know,we gotta get up early and catch the plane to New York.
我们早上要赶飞机
Yeah,it's a very large plane.
对，那架飞机很大
Why,what's the matter?
怎么了？